# **Enrico Gullotto**

Bangkok, Thailand | +66 954958909 | www.linkedin.com/in/enrico-gullotto-3523518b | enricogullotto@gmail.com

#### Personal Details:

Birth Date: 20 May 1981 | Nationality: Italian | Languages: Italian, English, French (Basic German & Indonesian)

## Food & Beverage and Restaurant Management Professional

Accomplished and driven leader with 15+ years of progressive experience in the food and beverage industry.

Demonstrated ability to direct all food and beverage employees, facilities, sales, and costs to maximize profit while achieving world class standards. Dedicated to delivering optimal guest experience by assessing customer needs, consistently meeting quality standards, and evaluating customer satisfaction. Engaging leader adept at establishing and maintaining open, collaborative relationships with entire food and beverage team, using passion for craft and skill in leading others to enable employees to continually exceed expectations. Proven success identifying opportunities to increase profits and create value by challenging existing processes, encouraging innovation, and driving necessary change.

- Marketing & Promotions
- Inventory Management
- Guest Satisfaction
- Budget Management & Profit Margins
- Employee Training & Coaching
- Supplier Relations & Negotiations
- Strategic Planning
- Resource Allocation
- Market Trends

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Destination Eats, Bangkok, Phuket, Pattaya

2017 - Present

#### **General Manager**

Oversee all food and beverage departments for Hooters and the Hard Rock Cafe, maintaining revenue, profitability, and quality goals. Lead team of up to 60 employees, including hiring and quarterly performance evaluations. Control operational measures and identify measures to cut waste, with full responsibility for profit and loss (P&L). Enforce compliance with sanitation and safety regulations. Manage food and beverage cost and menu engineering. Complete forecasting, budgeting, and sales projections. Establish and maintain positive relationships with suppliers. Administer marketing and promotion strategies, as well as social media.

- Instrumental in financial growth of 15% to 20% by implementing new promotions and staff incentives, as well as establishing deals with travel agencies for group bookings.
- Reduced costs up to 15% by renegotiating contracts with suppliers and by calculating more precise food and beverage costs.
- Streamlined labour force and decreased costs 10% while improving staff performance with new bonus plan.
- Enhanced efficiency by implementing new back office system for accounting, purchasing, and HR processes.

Monti at the Fullerton Pavilion, Singapore

2016 - 2017

## **Operation Manager**

Managed pre-opening operations for multi-concept venue along Marina Bay, including dining, bar, brunch, and happy hour. Developed overall vision and mission strategy to drive profitability. Oversaw venue remodelling and construction work, including licenses and designers. Established relationships with suppliers and negotiated contracts. Built high-performing team of 45 employees, including hiring and training. Created and executed marketing strategy to ensure business for new venue. Forecasted monthly and yearly sales projections. Managed beverage and wine inventory.

- Achieved revenue goals within three months, delivering \$500K in monthly sales.
- Increased number of events 20% by establishing strategic partnerships with associations, clubs, and wedding planners.
- Boosted revenue with new marketing strategies, including VIP card, monthly 'Monti by Night' event, Sunday brunch theme, and rooftop bar events.
- Restaurant was finalist for Wine and Dine best new restaurant.

# **Enrico Gullotto**

Page Two of Two

### Bistecca Tuscan Steakhouse, Singapore

2011 - 2016

#### **Restaurant Manager**

Directed all restaurant operations to deliver an excellent guest experience. Led team of 35 employees, including hiring, training, and employee development. Negotiated contracts with suppliers and managed bar/wine stock control. Administered sales growth, cost management, account management, and profit growth areas. Completed monthly and yearly sales revenue report as well as budgetary forecasting.

- Grew revenue 20% to 25% every year, from \$200K per month to \$350K per month.
- Reduced labour cost \$20K per month without affecting quality of service.
- Evaluated expenses and eliminated unnecessary costs, delivering savings of approximately \$15K per month.
- Restaurant was ranked as one of top five steakhouses in Singapore.

#### Kamasutra Corporation, Bali, Indonesia

2009 - 2011

#### **General Manager**

Oversaw all operational aspects for nightclub, bar, and restaurant, administering \$240K monthly budget. Supervised 110 employees, including hiring and training. Managed public relations and supplier relations. Researched and developed new business opportunities to continually drive growth.

- Increased revenue 15% at each outlet with new training methods, incentives, and happy hour promotions.
- Implemented wastage recording system that reduced food and beverage costs by 5% at each outlet.

Adriatico Bar and Restaurant, London, England

2007 - 2008

#### **Restaurant Manager**

Directed day-to-day operations, including order placement, work schedules, and customer service. Collaborated with chef to select and create menus and pricing. Maintained and repaired all restaurant equipment.

Additional experience as Assistant Manager for Alba Restaurant in London, England and as Head Waiter for Casa Mamma Restaurant in London, England.

### **EDUCATION**

**Advanced Diploma, Business Management** 

SDH Hospitality School, Singapore

**Diploma, Food and Beverage**I.P.P.S.A.R. Marco Polo, Genoa, Italy